# Amanda Barnes

# INTEGRATED CAMPAIGN MANAGER

7502 Woodley Rd, Henrico, VA, 23229

509.290.1966

abarnesmarie@gmail.com

# EDUCATION

BA, MARKETING MAJOR Eastern Washington University 2008-14

# KEY SKILLS

SEO Html & CSS Website Lead Generation Project Management Content Strategy Email Automation

# COMPUTER

Atlassian Cloud/ Jira Workflow Wordpress

Drupal

Sketch

Slack

Microsoft Product Suite SEO/Analytics/Webmaster Tools

Google Adwords MOZ

iMovie

Marketo

Mail Chimp

Constant Contact

Get Drip

Hootsuite

Social Media Platforms

# PROFILE

Digital Marketing Manager with over five years of experience.

Skilled in SEO, PPC, Google Analytics, social media, email automation, media buys, digital performance reporting, and working with various CMS systems such as Wordpress, Craft, and Drupal.

Strong marketing professional with a BA focused in Marketing from Eastern Washington University.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### INTEGRATED CAMPAIGN MANAGER

AVEPOINT INC.

FEBRUARY 2017-PRESENT

AvePoint is the Microsoft Cloud expert. Over 15,000 companies and 5 million-cloud users worldwide trust AvePoint to migrate, manage, and protect their Office 365 and SharePoint data.

- Managed global Adwords account. Brought CPL costs down from \$150/lead to \$75/lead in twelve months.
- Put together and launched email marketing and product drip campaigns
- Researched, oversaw, and managed creative deadlines for media buys.
- Developed SEO strategies that helped drive new business and improve search rankings for core products, services, and website content.
- Collaborated with AvePoint's content director and created a strategy that increased organic traffic by 22% in 12 months

# ACCOUNT COORDINATOR/ PROJECT MANAGER

HONEYBADGERS MARKETING GROUP

JANUARY 2016- APRIL 2017

Progressive marketing firm, whose business focus is web development and online marketing

- Ensured full project compliance with the client's requirements, deadlines and budget restraints
- Maintained direct day-to-day contact with clients.
- Monitored clients' market landscape and identified opportunities for growth.
- Led a virtual team of both designers and developers to complete website and landing page build-outs for clients
- Performed site analysis, keyword research and mapping, and assessed link building opportunities.
- Developed SEO strategies that helped drive new business and improve search rankings for core products, services, and website content
- Managed social media profiles and online presence for clients via social networking tools and strategies.

# **Amanda Barnes**

# INTEGRATED CAMPAIGN MANAGER

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (continued)

# MARKETING COORDINATOR

M.L. BELL CONSTRUCTION

FEBRUARY 2015- PRESENT

Commercial General Contractor that specializes in building restaurants, retail centers, preschools, and hotels.

- Designed and managed all advertisements for publications and sponsorships.
- Solidified brand and created consistency among advertising materials.
- Re-designed brochures, trade show banners, email templates and other materials to better match new branding.
- Attended Trade shows and sought out new business.
- Enacted email marketing campaigns targeted towards growing specific divisions.
- Led efforts driven towards keeping M.L. Bell Construction's name in the press. Such
  efforts consisted of speaking to reporters about our growth, sponsoring and volunteering
  with different organizations, submitting the company to different city-wide lists that led
  to networking and new business opportunities and hosting in-house events to touch base
  with both vendors and clients.

# MARKETING COORDINATOR

SCAFCO STEEL STUD CORPORATION

APRIL 2014- JANUARY 2015

Steel Manufacture that manufactures both steel studs for commercial construction and grain silos for agricultural businesses

- Planned and coordinated trades shows and travel for our domestic and international sales staff
- Performed market research and worked to acquire new contacts for different regions in
- Worked with Spokane Commerce to set up and execute Gold Key Service in Tanzania.
   Gold keys are created to help businesses expand into new regions globally.
- Prepared and managed press releases surrounding new products and procedures.
- Planned a three-day conference that brought in business partners from seventeen countries for educational seminars, sales training, and a tour of our company's headquarters.
- Managed Google Adwords, Bing, and social media

# MARKETING INTERN

THE SEATTLE WUNDERMAN NETWORK

JUNE 2013-AUGUST 2013

The Seattle office of the #1 mobile marketer and digital agency network in the world, Wunderman, serves two of the networks largest clients: T-Mobile and Microsoft. The Direct Marketing Association named T-Mobile the 2013 Marketer of the Year

 As a culminating project, I worked as a member of a seven-person intern team on the creation of a contact acquisition plan for The Microsoft Store. We presented this plan to Wunderman executives and Microsoft clients at the end of the internship as a mock RFP.